Hey guys, we come back.
I hope you're gone through the previous video
and I hope it was pretty enlightening for you
because see, to really learn data engineering,
you must be getting your hands dirty.
When you create something on your own,
you don't easily forget that.
Okay? Anyway, let's continue our discussion.
Now, as I said, the next few videos are very important.
We'll talk about the development lifecycle.
So what exactly happened before the development begins?
You gotta know about this. So the first step is that,
you know, you load of data here, right?
You, you give all the data to the data analysts, right?
It's right here. The two years they ask for,
you have it here, the zone data is also here, in fact, okay?
And you have built the appropriate tables in blue catalog.
So they're able to query, and I told you
that the H-V-F-H-V table has a pickup
and drop off location id,
and they will really want to see the right actual locations.
And so they will want to join on the, this table
with the zone table based on the location id.
Okay? So here's an example query that, uh, they would've run
by joining the H-V-F-H-V table
and the zone table,
and they can now see the data
with the right pickup location, the manton, the zone,
the drop location, all of that is right here, in fact.
So they have done all sort of analysis on the data
and uh, they are, they are now ready
to give you the requirements
because they exactly know what they need
for optimizing revenue and driver operations.
So their researcher notes would look like this.
You know, data comes monthly
and for our analysis for building our reports, you know,
on tools, reporting tools such as QuickSight, AWS,
QuickSight or Tableau is a reporting tools.
Should we build the reports monthly basis or daily basis?
And they would want to look at
what are they trying to identify?
What exactly are they trying to
optimize, right?
Do we have some, um, use cases mentioned here?
You can read, read through them later.
So the point I'm going to say, trying to say is that,
you know, you have done your work, you provide,
provide them the data, and now they have analyzed the data
and they are ready to give you requirements.
So what's the next step?
The next step is that they will get into a meeting with you.
Okay? The data engineer team,
you are in the data engineer team anyway,
and as a grade data engineer, you wanna propose
for tier actually three tier structure.
In fact, three tier structure in data lake, okay?
Now what do I mean by this?
Seeing data lake, you got the data in the raw folder, right?
These are, these are just raw,
these is just a raw data, okay?
That is coming from the source, okay?
Now obviously data has to be cleaned,
data could have null data.
I mean, there could be blank
Values in the fields,
and there could be some business rules that you'll have
to kind of validate the data against.
Okay? We'll talk about that shortly.
In fact, what the business rules are,
what data validation is shortly.
But you get the point that raw is only for the raw data,
which is coming from source as is.
Now, when you wanna validate the data
and also clean it, you can't keep that data, the clean data,
the data, which is validated back in raw, okay?
You gotta move that to another folder called as curated,
right here, in fact, curated layer, okay?
So in the curated layer, you will not only claims data,
welded data, but you will also be
implementing some business rules.
Okay? I'll talk to you about
that shortly, don't worry about that.
So that is the next layer, raw and then curated.
And then you propose the aggregate
for the final aggregated data.
You wanna aggregate data based on
the daily operations, right?
So you say that we are gonna be storing the daily data in
aggregated layer for you to aggregate.
And because they have told you
that they will want data in daily aggregations,
you will say that, okay?
In the raw, it comes in a monthly format anyway.
If you look at the year
and then you have monthly data in curated
and in aggregated, we'll store data in the daily format
in a daily partition format.
That's how we're gonna be organizing the data.
And then you ask them
to provide a mapping specification, right?
How do you really want us
to transform the data when you move the data from
your raw layer to curated, okay,
what business rules should we implement?
What validation should we do on the data?
You ask them, you give me Excel sheet
where you put down all of these things to us.
Also let us know how we can move data from curated
to the aggregated layer.
So give us a mapping sheet for that as well.
So they'll take, they'll take some time
and uh, finally, uh, they'll get back to you
and they're gonna give you a mapping sheet, okay?
So we'll discuss all of that in the next video as to
how the mapping sheet looks like, you know,
what is mentioned in that
and what you do with that in the next video.